

901 Kains Ave. Albany, CA 94706

□ (+1) 781-635-8799 | douglas.rogers@gmail.com | oafxjzs | odouglasrogers

# Summary.

Entrepreneurial engineer and product design leader with a broad range of experience over 20 years, from building companies and teams to full-stack development to product and UX design: Founded and grown multiple businesses to more than \$1MM yearly revenue with 1 exit. Advised CEOs of billion dollar companies on technology, business strategy, and startup acquisitions totaling over \$50MM. Built a logistics platform to manage 500+ photographers, 250+ monthly shoots, and 1.3MM+ photographs. Co-founded eCommerce business grossing over \$3MM yearly revenue.

Y Combinator alumnus, engineer, entrepreneur, and advisor to startups. I understand business as well as technology.

## Goals

To work with a team of highly skilled engineers, designers, and product managers solving problems that matter. To expand my existing skillset of product and user experience design, software engineering, and strategic advisory into new areas such as developer enablement, community building, and performance optimization at scale. To create amazing products and services that exceed both customer expectations and business objectives.

# Work Experience

Applico, Inc.

NYC / SF / Remote

Boutique advisory firm specializing in guiding enterprise CEOs to grow and succeed in the modern economy

 DIRECTOR
 Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2023

- Directed technical diligence and vetting process for multiple startup acquisitions totaling over \$50MM in successfully completed deals.
- Personally advised CEOs and C-level executives of billion dollar companies on how to leverage their existing core business strengths to create new revenue streams through partnerships, strategic investments, and acquisitions.
- Led high-intensity 3-month client project teams to identify platform-based business opportunities with 100% client contract continuation rate.
- Evaluated and personally spoke with founders of 250+ startups to assess team, tech, and business model relative to client's strategic business goals.

### Pretty Instant, Inc. [Acquired by Snappr]

Boston, MA

Y Combinator backed professional photographer staffing company with national coverage

Co-founder / CTO

Jan. 2015 - Oct. 2019

- Built side-project into a company generating \$1MM yearly revenue with +60% YoY growth.
- Grew product team from 1 to 5 developers and designers, led engineering and design from concept to launch, operation and iteration.
- Created a Ruby on Rails staffing and logistics app that allowed a 3 person team to handle the logistics of 250+ monthly photography shoots, 500+ photographers, and 2000+ clients. Integrated with more than a dozen 3rd party applications including AWS, Salesforce, Slack, Stripe, Google Maps and Google Calendar.
- Designed and built a robust RESTful API allowing for 3rd party booking and integration
- Created a "Roaming Photobooth" iPad app with Ruby on Rails back-end that received photos from a wifi-enabled DSLR camera, optimized and branded them, and allowed the user to email, text, or tweet the images in under 30 seconds. Outperformed Canon's own iOS app in speed and stability, even with limited internet connectivity.
- Created entire design system including a composable library of form controls to allow rapid iteration of form design optimizing for clients making multiple bookings, increasing rebooking rate by 30%.
- Reduced photo delivery time by 50% by creating a dedicated photo uploader application capable of processing uploads up to 400Gb that gracefully handled slow connections, network interruptions, and browser restarts.

#### **Laboratory Supply Network**

Atkinson, NH

Company building a suite of online marketplaces focused on selling lab equipment

Co-Founder / Advisor

Jan. 2015 - Present

- Currently generating over \$3MM annual revenue, with 50% YoY growth.
- Technical advisor for online and purchase order management app, under negotiation for licensing agreement to become stand-alone product and revenue stream.

#### CO-FOUNDER / ENGINEERING LEAD

Jun. 2014 - Jan. 2015

- Designed and built suite of configurable Shopify themes, allowing for rapid deployment of new stores as product supply diversified.
- Created custom deployment pipeline to automate theme and feature improvements across multiple stores.
- · Created custom javascript on-page product filtering functionality that extends beyond ability of Shopify's Liquid templates.
- Doubled size of potential customer base by implementing quoting/purchase order functionality alongside existing Shopify Checkout.

Indie Ambassador Boston. MA

Online community and portfolio site for creative professionals

CO-FOUNDER / CTO Aug 2011 - Jan 2015

- Led initiative to streamline product roadmap from all-in-one platform to focused online portfolio/electronic press kit application.
- After pivot, created first product, Presskit.to, from conception to launch in 3 weeks using PHP CodeIgniter framework.
- · Launched at SXSW 2012 with 3 showcases sponsored by Shure Microphones and Magner's Irish Cider.
- Grew Presskit.to app to 6k sign ups and \$5k monthly revenue in the first 6 months with zero marketing budget.
- Featured by HypeBot, RackSpace, and Berklee College of Music.

Quirk Auto Dealers

Braintree, MA

Top 3 largest auto dealership chain in the northeast

DIRECTOR OF IT DEVELOPMENT

Dec 2006 - Jan 2011

- Hired 5 people: 1 developer, 1 designer, 2 eBay specialists, and an assistant
- Initiated the creation of QuirkParts.com eBay store to facilitate the sale of the extensive parts inventory online. Hired 2 eBay experts to manage the listings, generating \$50,000 per month in revenue at time of departure.
- Created an in house leaderboard application for sales staff replacing a manual whiteboard and saving over \$10k in human labor per week.
- · Automated email service reminders, yielding a 20% increase in appointment scheduling.

WEB DEVELOPER / ONLINE MARKETER

Jun 2006 - Dec 2006

- Created QuirkService.com, one of the first dedicated websites to handle service requests, specials, and appointment scheduling across all brands.
- Increased traffic across all franchise sites 30-50%, generating qualified leads for less than half the cost per lead compared to 3rd party lead sources.
- Managed a monthly PPC budget of \$30k that outperformed more than \$100k in offline ad spend in both lead quantity, and quality.
- Increased website lead generation by 50% YoY by implementing latest SEO and PPC strategies. Managed Google Adwords spend of \$50,000/mo.

Web Developer Nov 2005 - Jun 2006

- Directed all web design and development, including but not limited to 13 individual customer facing dealership sites and custom internal CMS. Increased online lead generation 10x in first year.
- Designed and administered over a dozen full-featured auto dealer franchise websites resulting in a 500% increase in traffic after the first year.
- Worked with Dealer.com and ADP to create an automated first-in-the-country unified inventory search across all brands, both new and used, updated hourly (previous standard was 2 days).

### **Earth Institute @ Columbia University**

New York, NY

Research, education, and practical solutions helping to guide the world onto a path toward sustainability

PHP Developer Jun 2004 - Sep 2004

• Developed custom web based PHP-MySQL applications on Linux-based Apache web server.

UPS New York, NY

American multinational package delivery and supply chain management company

COLDFUSION DEVELOPER Jan 2003 - Apr 2003

• Developed custom inventory tracking application with ColdFusion and MySQL.

**Instinet** New York, NY

Institutional, agency-model brokerage firm

JSP Developer Jun 2002 - Sep 2002

• Created high-speed stock trade auditing application with JSP to automatically analyze end-of-day trade reports.

Media 3 Technologies Pembroke, MA

Web hosting company

COLDFUSION DEVELOPER / WEBMASTER Jul 1998 - Aug 2000

• As employee #7, maintained website and developed ColdFusion applications to automate various internal business processes.

## Education

Y Combinator Mountain View, CA

**W15 BATCH** 2010

## Stevens Institute of Technology Hoboken, NJ

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Engineering Sep 2000 - Jun 2005

March 11, 2023 Douglas E. Rogers · Résumé